GYEONGBOK LEE

alias_n@live.com · https://antest1.github.io/

[last updated: Jul 2022]

My research interests lie in the field of knowledge representation and model interpretability on natural language processing and modeling for various tasks based on log data. I'm also interested in the techniques for deploying deep learning models in various environments.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

FEB 2019 - PRESENT

AI RESEARCHER, APPLIED AI LAB, NCSOFT

currently in Sequence Modeling Team

Research topics includes:

- Explainable AI (XAI) in Natural Language Processing Model
- User Knowledge Modeling for Learning Path Recommendation
- Model Design/Implementation for User Recommendation System
- Large-scale Log-based Methodology for Game Bot Detection
- Log Abstraction with Process Mining and Graph Summarization

JUL 2018 - OCT 2018

INTERNSHIP, CLOVA AI, NAVER

Topic: SQuAD 2.0, Debugging QA Model

Role: model design and implementation (Keras/Tensorflow), experiment design

AUG 2016 - JUN 2017

INDUSTRY-ACADEMIC COOPERATION PROJECT, NAVER

Topic: Query Intention Representation using Deep Neural Networks

Role: model design and implementation (PyTorch), build web framework (Bootstrap, Flask, etc)

EDUCATION

SEP 2016 - FEB 2019

M.S., COMPUTER SCIENCE, YONSEI UNIVERSITY

Supervisor: Prof. Seung-won Hwang

Thesis: Explainable Machine Reading Comprehension Framework for Model Debugging

MAR 2013 - AUG 2016

B.S, COMPUTER SCIENCE, YONSEI UNIVERSITY

Summa Cum Laude (GPA 4.08/4.3)

PUBLICATIONS

 SQuAD2-CR: Semi-supervised Annotation for Cause and Rationales for Unanswerability in SQuAD 2.0

Gyeongbok Lee, Seung-won Hwang, Hyunsouk Cho

LREC - The International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation, 2020

• Explanatory and Actionable Debugging for Machine Learning: A TableQA Demonstration

Minseok Cho, Gyeongbok Lee, Seung-won Hwang

SIGIR (Demonstration) - Annual Conference of the Association for Computing Machinery Special Interest Group in Information Retrieval, 2019

QADiver: Interactive Framework for Diagnosing QA Models

Gyeongbok Lee, Sungdong Kim, Seung-won Hwang

AAAI (Demonstration) - Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence, 2019

 Visual Choice of Plausible Alternatives: An Evaluation of Image-based Commonsense Causal Reasoning

Jinyoung Yeo, {**Gyeongbok Lee**, Gengyu Wang}*, Seungtaek Choi, Hyunsouk Cho, Reinald Kim Amplayo, Seung-won Hwang (*co-first authors)

LREC - The International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation, 2018

AWARDS

JUN 2017

KISTI PRESIDENT AWARD FOR SW IMPLEMENTATION/DEMO CONTEST

KCC 2017 conference (Domestic Competition)

Topic: KB inference for Action-driven Chatbots

APR 2017

TOP WINNER OF BIG 2017 CUP CHALLENGE

BIG 2017 conference co-located with WWW 2017 (International Competition)

Topic: IsA relationship extraction from large-scale concept graphs

JUN 2016

EXCELLENCE AWARD FOR GRADUATION EXHIBITION

Dept. of Computer Science, Yonsei University

Topic: Development of REST Service for Author-Paper Identification

APR 2016

TOP WINNER OF BIG 2016 CUP CHALLENGE

BIG 2016 conference co-located with WWW 2017 (International Competition)

Topic: Author-Paper Identification from large-scale heterogenous academic graphs

NOV 2015

EXCELLENCE AWARD FOR GRADUATION EXHIBITION

Dept. of Computer Science, Yonsei University

Topic: Web Framework Development for Comparison Analysis of Classification Methods in

Sensor Data Stream

TEACHING EXPERIENCES

SPRING 2018

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Yonsei University, Seoul CSI4108: ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE (Undergraduate)

SPRING 2016

STUDENT TUTOR

Tutoring Program in Yonsei University, Seoul CSI2109: INTERNET PROGRAMMING (Undergraduate) Awarded as the **Outstanding Tutoring Team**

FALL 2015

STUDENT TUTOR

Tutoring Program in Yonsei University, Seoul CSI2102: OBJECT-ORIENTED PROGRAMMING (Undergraduate) Awarded as the **Outstanding Tutoring Team**

SPRING 2015

STUDENT TUTOR

Tutoring Program in Yonsei University, Seoul CSI2109: INTERNET PROGRAMMING (Undergraduate) Awarded as the **Outstanding Tutor**

SCHOLARSHIPS

- Internal Scholarship (Graduate, Yonsei University)
 Fall 2016, Spring 2017, Fall 2017
- NAVER M.S Student Fellowship (2016)
- National Science and Technology Scholarship (KOSAF)
 Fall 2013, Spring 2015, Fall 2015, Spring 2016
- Internal Scholarship (Undergraduate, Yonsei University)
 Spring 2013, Spring 2014, Fall 2014

PERSONAL PROJECTS & SERVICES

DEC 2016 - PRESENT

KCANOTIFY VIEWER APPLICATION FOR KANCOLLE ANDROIDAL

Github: https://github.com/antest1/kcanotify

Role: development (Android, PHP), UI design, user support

MAR 2019 - PRESENT

GOTOBROWSER ANDROID BROWSER FOR KANCOLLE 2ND PHASE (HTML5)

Github: https://antest1.github.io/GotoBrowser/

Role: development (Android, Javascript), UI design, user support

2021, 2022

AAAI PROGRAM COMMITTEE MEMBER (REVIEWER)

Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence included in the top 25% of Program Committee Members (2021)

2020, 2022

LREC SCIENTIFIC COMMITTEE MEMBER (REVIEWER)

The International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation

SKILLS

- Programming Language: Python, Java, Javascript
- Tools: Web Frameworks (Bootstrap, Flask, Sanic), Deep Learning Frameworks (PyTorch, Keras, Tensorflow), Mobile Development Environments (Android SDK, Java), Data Analysis (Hive, Spark)